{"Topic": "Indian Prime Ministers", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "How many Indian Prime Ministers have died while in office?", "op1": "1", "op2": "2", "op3": "3", "op4": "4", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the acting Prime Minister of India twice on the death of Jawaharlal Nehru and Lal Bahadur Shastri?", "op1": "Purshottam Das Tandon", "op2": "Gulzari Lal Nanda", "op3": "Morarjee Desai", "op4": "Chandrashekhar", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the first Prime Minister to visit Siachen?", "op1": "Dr. Manmohan Singh", "op2": "Rajiv Gandhi", "op3": "Atal Bihari Vajpayee", "op4": "Lal Bahadur Shastri", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which schedule to the Constitution of India carries the form of oath or affirmation for the Prime Minister of India?", "op1": "Second", "op2": "Third", "op3": "Fourth", "op4": "Fifth", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the official residence of the Prime Minister of India?", "op1": "No. 1 Safdarjung Road", "op2": "No. 10 Janpath", "op3": "No. 1 Akbar Road", "op4": "No. 7 Race Course Road", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which Indian Prime Minister was the first to be awarded the Bharat Ratna posthumously?", "op1": "Lal Bahadur Shastri", "op2": "Indira Gandhi", "op3": "Rajiv Gandhi", "op4": "Morarjee Gandhi", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Birth anniversary of which Prime Minister is observed as Sadbhawna Diwas?", "op1": "Lal Bahadur Shastri", "op2": "Indira Gandhi", "op3": "Rajiv Gandhi", "op4": "PV Narasimha Rao", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following did not hold any other cabinet post prior to becoming the Prime Minister?", "op1": "Lal Bahadur Shastri", "op2": "Indira Gandhi", "op3": "Rajiv Gandhi", "op4": "PV Narsimha Rao", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Match the birthdays with the Prime Ministers", "op1": "A - 2; B - 3; C - 1; D - 4", "op2": "A - 4; B - 3; C - 1; D - 2", "op3": "A - 4; B - 1; C - 3; D - 2", "op4": "A - 3; B - 2; C - 1; D - 4", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "ch of the above is/are correct?", "op1": "Jawahar Lal Nehru", "op2": "Indira Gandhi", "op3": "PV Narasimha Rao", "op4": "Manmohan Singh", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the first Prime Minister to present the Union Budget?", "op1": "Indira Gandhi", "op2": "H.D. Deve Gowda", "op3": "Manmohan Singh", "op4": "I.K. Gujral"}, {"Question": "Arrange the following in ascending order of lengths of their total tenure as Prime Ministers?", "op1": "2 - 3 - 1 - 4", "op2": "3 - 2 - 1 - 4", "op3": "3 - 1 - 4 - 2", "op4": "2 - 1 - 4 - 3", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which constituency did Prime Minister Lal Bahadu Shastri represent?", "op1": "Varanasi", "op2": "Rae Bareli", "op3": "Allahabad", "op4": "Lucknow", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who administered the oath of office to the first Prime Minister of India, Shri Jawaharlal Nehru?", "op1": "Lord Mountbatten", "op2": "C. Rajagopalachari", "op3": "Rajendra Prasad", "op4": "Justice HL Kania", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "How many Prime Ministers have been awarded the Bharat Ratna till date (i.e. May 2014)?", "op1": "3", "op2": "4", "op3": "5", "op4": "6", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who was the only Prime Minister of India to be awarded the Nishan-e-Pakistan, Pakistan's highest civilian honour?", "op1": "Atal Bihari Vajpayee", "op2": "Morarji Desai", "op3": "Indira Gandhi", "op4": "PV Narasimha Rao", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following is/was the oldest to take the oath as the Prime Minister of India?", "op1": "Atal Bihari Vajpayee", "op2": "Manmohan Singh", "op3": "Morarji Desai", "op4": "PV Narasimha Rao", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following Prime Ministers was administered the oath of office by the Vice President (then acting President) B.D. Jatti?", "op1": "H.D. Deve Gowda", "op2": "Indira Gandhi", "op3": "Charan Singh", "op4": "Morarji Desai", "Answer": 2}]}